Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer, where we open up with the 10
Commandments that God had written for
the whole world to keep. Brother Tanzel.
And God spake all these words saying,
I am the Lord thy God, which have
brought thee out of the land of Egypt,
out of the house of bondage. Thou shalt
have no other gods before me. Thou shalt
not make unto thee any graven image, or
any likeness of anything that is in
heaven above, or that is in the earth
beneath, or that is in the water under
the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain.
For the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain.
Remember the sabbath day, to keep it
holy. Six days shalt thou labour, and do
all thy work. But the seventh day is the
sabbath of the Lord thy God. In it thou
shalt not do any work, thou, nor thy
son, nor thy daughter, nor thy man
servant, nor thy maid servant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates.
For in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the sabbath day, and
hallowed it. Honour thy father and thy
mother:
that thy days may be long upon the land
which the Lord thy God giveth thee.
Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt not
commit adultery. Thou shalt not steal.
Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbour. Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbour's house, thou shalt
not covet thy neighbour's wife, nor his
man servant, nor his maid servant, nor
his ox, nor his ass, nor any thing that
is thy neighbour's.
We read Exodus 20:1-17,
and may the Lord have a blessing to the
reading of his
In Jesus' name we pray. Amen.
Amen.
So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time.
Questions we will not answer are the
vague, as well as the long scripture
questions, and questions of debate. We
are not here to debate. We are here to
spread the true gospel of Jesus. So
please, be as direct as possible with
your questions so we can be as direct as
possible with our answers out of the
King James Bible. No other Bibles or
books will be acknowledged on this
program. Also keep in mind, this is a
live stream, so feel free to send in
your questions that pertain to
everlasting life. We just asking you to
please keep them to a two scripture
maximum. But let me introduce to you the
family that's on the panel this evening.
We got brother Jerome.
Rest in peace.
Brother Dre.
Good evening.
Brother Julius.
All right. Brother Julius.
Good evening, everybody.
Brother Tanzel.
Good evening, everyone.
Sister Deborah.
Good evening.
Brother Shawn.
And we have the guest caller with us,
and I'm brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question of the
evening?
Yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Amazing Israelite asked, in Daniel 11:5
and 6, who is the king's daughter of the
south and the king of the north?
All right, so in that Daniel 11:5 and 6,
who is the kings of the daughter of the
south and the kings of the north? Let's
go there, brother Tanzel. Daniel 11,
verse 5 and 6. And the guest caller will
take it from there.
And the king of the south shall be
strong. And one of his princes, and he
shall be strong above him,
and have dominion, and his dominion
shall be a great dominion.
And in the end of years they shall join
themselves together.
For the king's daughter of the south
shall come to the kings of the north to
make an agreement.
But she shall not retain the power of
the arm,
neither shall he
stand, nor his arm. But she shall be
given up, and they that brought her, and
he that begat her, and he that
strengthened her in these times.
Well, the truth of the matter is, the
Bible won't tell you who the king the
daughter of the king of the
uh uh
of the south is.
It's not written in the Bible, so I
can't tell you either.
I'll have to say
>> I don't know who she is.
Anybody else know?
Where it's written in the Bible. I don't
It's not written in the Bible.
All right.
We're going to leave it right there as
we move on to our next question.
Next question. Annika Masala asked, how
do we perceive visions?
Since we know angels delivered the
Lord's message, is it the mind, spirit,
or soul that perceives visions?
All right, so brother Julius, how is it
that we perceive visions?
Go ahead.
A true vision from the Lord will be
clear.
It's going to be understandable,
and it must align with the written word
of God.
Now, you said with the
uh mind, spirit, or soul. The soul is
the body. The mind or the brain is is in
uh is inside the soul.
Cuz you are a living soul.
And the spirit is the word of God. But
it could also be the angel that brings
the word of God. Now, you used three
words. You said uh is it the Did you use
the word vision? You used the mean word
mind, and you used the word perceive.
I'm going to go to a scripture that's
going to cover that. Acts chapter 10.
That's going to cover all three of those
words.
Acts chapter 10. How do we perceive a
vision?
The Lord says he works through his
angels.
And he works
through your mind
that the angel brings the word to you.
This word the word of God, too. Acts 10,
and this is in the days of Cornelius,
the first Gentile that was brought into
the New Testament church by the hand of
Peter.
Acts 10, uh Tanzel, good evening,
brother. Read verses 9 and 10. Acts 10,
9 and 10. Would you get it, my brother?
Go ahead and read. Let's pay attention
in what we're reading. Acts 10, 9 and
10. Go ahead.
On the morrow, as they went on their
journey, and drew nigh unto the city,
Peter went up upon the house top to pray
about the sixth hour. Go ahead. He
became very hungry, and would have
eaten. But while they made ready, he
fell into a trance. So he fell into a
trance. He's having a vision, sisters
and brothers. Skip all the way down.
Read the whole chapter on your own. Skip
all the way down to verse 17, cuz this
man wants to uh be a part of uh the New
Testament church, but he wants to find
out what he must do, him and his family,
to get uh
into the kingdom of God. And the Lord
said, "Go find Peter, he'll tell you
what you need to do."
So Peter fell into a trance.
Or he had a vision. Go ahead at verse
17, and go ahead.
Now while Peter doubted and doubted in
himself what this vision which he had
seen should mean, Now, there's the word
vision. So the trance is the vision.
He's having a vision. Go ahead. And he
he doubted in himself. That's his mind.
Doubt is in your mind.
Now while Peter doubted in himself what
the visions which he had should mean
seen should mean, go ahead.
Behold, the men which were sent from
Cornelius had made inquiry for Simon's
house, and stood before the gate. Now,
as time went on, the Lord revealed the
vision to Peter. Verse 34.
Verse 34.
When you get it, go ahead. Then Peter
opened Go ahead, brother.
Then Peter opened his mouth, and said,
"Of a truth I perceive that God is no
respecter of persons." "Of a truth I
perceive that God is no
respecter of persons."
So now, you got the word perceive. You
have to have that. And then you got We
read the word vision. And then we read
the word uh um um
mind or the thoughts or within himself.
But how do you know
if it's true? It's got to align with
scripture.
Let's go to 1 John, the fourth chapter.
1 John 4.
And when you get it, Tanzel, read verse
1.
Because you have a bad vision don't mean
that it's from God. Go ahead.
Beloved, believe not every spirit, but
try the spirit whether they are of God.
Why?
Because many false prophets are gone out
into the world. Cuz false prophets have
visions, too. But they're not of the
Lord.
But this one was of the Lord because it
was successful and the angel told him,
"Go find Peter. He will tell you what
you need to do." So, the true vision
from the Lord will be clear, it's going
to be coherent or understandable, it's
going to align with the word of God
because the word of God said that the
Gentiles must come into the church, also
Cornelius being the first one. I hope
that helped.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Whosoever will, let them come. Yes, sir.
All right. We're going to move on to our
next question.
Moving on, Mel and Natural Journey asks,
"Can I get a letter, excuse me, from
IOG to show an employer that I can't
work on the Sabbath day and that I
observe the Sabbath?"
I'm sure, yeah, you can get a letter.
Um saying that um
that you observe the Sabbath day and you
don't want to work on the Sabbath day.
They may or may not acknowledge your
letter, but um
you can get one.
And as a bonus on that letter, we'll
also be the feast days.
So, you'll have those all-inclusive as
well. But yeah, you can get a letter.
You call the office and um
inquire
or call in the office.
And that's all I got.
And we hope that that answered your
question as we move on to our next
question.
Moving on, Zion asks, "If the tree of
knowledge of good and evil was Satan,
could you explain Genesis 2:19,
Genesis 3:1,
and Genesis 3:14?"
All right, brother Dre, what you say
about this tree of knowledge of good and
evil that was indeed Satan?
Yes, it was and we're going to look at
that. Let's go to Genesis
uh 2.
You said 19, we're going to read that,
but that's not what you're looking for.
You're looking for verse 9. Go ahead and
read it, brother Tenzil.
And out of the ground the Lord God
formed every beast of the field and
every fowl of the air and brought them
unto Adam to see what he would call
them. And whatsoever Adam called every
living creature, that was the name
thereof. So, you wasn't looking for 19,
you're looking for 9. Read that,
brother. Go ahead.
And out of the ground made the Lord God
to grow every tree that is pleasant to
the sight
and good for food. The tree of life also
in the midst of the garden and the tree
of knowledge of good and evil. So, he
talked about all the trees, but he also
said also the tree of the of life and
the tree of the knowledge of good and
evil. Now, this was in the midst of the
garden, it said, right? Now, let's go to
that Genesis 3. Genesis 3, read verse 1
and we're going to read verse 14. Go
ahead, brother.
Now, the serpent was more subtle than
any beast of the field which the Lord
God had made.
And he said unto the woman,
"Yeah, hath God said, 'Ye shall not eat
of every tree of the garden?'" Now, read
verse 14. Go ahead.
And the Lord God said unto the serpent,
"Because thou hast done this, thou art
cursed above all cattle
and above every beast of the field. Upon
thy belly shall thou go and dust shall
thou eat all the days of thy life." Now,
we're going to look at this serpent
here. Let's go to Revelation 12 and read
verse 9. Revelation 12 and 9, we're
going to identify him.
Read that when you get there, brother.
And the great dragon was cast out, that
old serpent called the devil
and Satan
>> he called?
The devil. He's called the devil, that
old serpent called the devil and Satan.
Go ahead.
which deceived the whole world.
He was cast out into the earth and his
angels were cast out with him. So, we
see that this serpent right here is the
devil. But let's look let's go over to
Isaiah 66 now. And this is the last
place, Isaiah 66. We're going to read
verses 16 and 17. Remember that tree in
the midst of the garden. Go ahead. When
you get it, Isaiah 66:16
and 17. Go ahead.
For by fire and by his sword will the
Lord plead with all flesh.
And the slain of the Lord shall be many.
So, the Lord is coming and he is going
to plead with all flesh
and he's going to do judgment and the
slain of the Lord shall be many. Go
ahead.
And they that sanctify themselves and
purify themselves in the garden behind
one tree in the midst, eating swine's
flesh and the abomination and the mouse
shall be consumed together, saith the
Lord. So, those that are standing behind
that one tree in the midst
eating swine's flesh and the abomination
and the mouse will be consumed together.
What is that one tree in the midst? We
just read about it in Genesis. Mhm.
>> So, that is identifying him both ways,
okay? That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answers Faith's question as we
move on to our next one.
Next one, Be Alert says, "I have people
debate debate me on how do I know the
Sabbath is on Saturdays
because the Hebrew calendar has been
changed thousands of years ago. How do
we know the Roman calendar days are
correct?"
Well, the Julius.
First of all,
it it's not worth debating because
you're not going to come to an
agreement.
The Let's look at what the Bible says.
Let's Let's Let's get this out the way.
Let's go to 1 Corinthians, the 14th
chapter, Tenzil.
1 Corinthians, the 14th chapter. I could
easily tell you cuz God said it, but we
could read that later.
1 Corinthians cuz but you got people
that just don't believe. So, I don't
even debate with those kind of things.
1 Corinthians 14, give me one verse.
Verse 14.
Uh chapter 14 and verse 33. 33. Yep,
verse 33.
For God is not the author of confusion,
but of peace, as in all churches of the
saints.
God is not the author of confusion.
Let's go to the Romans, the third
chapter.
Come out to Hebrew calendar calendar
been changed.
Romans 3, one verse, verse 4. What it
say?
God forbid. Yeah. Let God be true, but
every man a liar, as it is written,
that thou mightest be justified in thy
saying and mightest overcome when thou
art judged. And might overcome.
That thou be justified. Let's justify
this thing. Let's go to the Bible.
That's if they believing in the Bible.
You don't need to debate people that
don't believe in the Bible.
Let's go into Exodus.
Let's go to Exodus.
Oh.
Because you'll be all day worried and
debating with people
about stuff. Exodus, the 20th chapter.
Exodus, the 20th chapter. Pick it up at
verse 1 and then we're going to skip.
And God spake all these words, saying,
>> Now, the book said, "Let God be true and
every man a liar," right? Right.
And God is not the author of confusion.
What did God say? Skip down to verse 8.
Go ahead.
Remember the Sabbath day to keep it
holy. Uh-huh. Six days shall thou labor
and do all thy work.
But the seventh day is the Sabbath of
the Lord thy God. Now, that's good,
brother.
The seventh day is He told you in Exodus
by the hand of Moses and the same the
same Moses He told you in Genesis
chapter 2.
Genesis chapter 2, go back to the
beginning quickly. Genesis chapter 2.
Genesis chapter 2,
verse 1 because the Bible God is
consistent. He is not the author of
confusion, man is. Genesis 2 and 1. Go
ahead.
Thus the heaven and the earth were
finished and all the host of them.
Uh-huh. And on the seventh day God ended
his work which he had made.
And he rested on the seventh day from
all his work which he had made.
And God blessed the seventh day and
sanctified it because in it he had
rested from all his work which God
created and made. So, now,
the Lord numbered his days
and he called the seventh day the
Sabbath, which means the day of rest.
Right. So, therefore, man gave you
Saturday. Who did that? Said they
trusted the Romans, the Romans gave you
Saturday. The Romans gave you Sunday
through
Sunday through
Sunday
through
uh
Monday through Sunday.
All of those are Roman days. Our
calendar is a Roman calendar. So, the
Roman calendar was started by King
Romulus. He created the calendar. In the
original Roman calendar, since the
Hebrew calendar been made 1,000 years
ago. No. No. No. No. The Babylonians
observed a Hebrew calendar because the
Hebrew calendar have 12 months of 30
days in each month. So did the
Babylonian calendar. The Romans'
original calendar had 10 months
beginning in March.
Okay? Beginning in March, sister
brothers.
From March to December.
Julius Caesar came along and added
January and February to
to fill in the winter period. So, it
wasn't the Hebrew calendar that changed.
It was the Roman calendar that changed.
And people say, "I don't believe it."
Well, yes, you do because you celebrate
your birthday at the appointed time on
the Roman calendar each year.
Right. So,
let's get the facts straight. Find out
who changed what.
Just like the whole world kept the
Sabbath day until
the Romans came and changed it in 321
AD. Right.
>> of that, Cornelius. So, don't debate
over things. It's fruitless. They don't
believe. Believe what the book say. And
as he read, God is not the author of
confusion. Man is.
That's all I got.
Right.
Thank you for that, brother. Hope that
answered their question. Next question.
Next question. Ran64 says, "There is a
camp out there saying that when the
heavens roll back
becomes black and the moon becomes blood
and the sun no longer gives it light,
that is or there are nuclear bombs
exploding in the earth.
True?"
They should put true or false at the end
of that. Guest caller.
First thing First thing is
Let's go into Revelations
sixth chapter and look at that.
We're going to see if we can
get a nuclear anything going on.
Revelation
chapter six and start at verse 12.
You can read it when you get it.
>> and 12.
Mhm.
And I beheld when he had opened the
sixth seal, and lo, there was a great
earthquake.
And the sun became black as sackcloth of
hair.
And the moon became as blood.
And the stars of heaven fell into the
earth.
Even as a fig tree casteth her untimely
figs when she is shaken of a mighty
wind.
And the heaven departed as a scroll when
it is rolled together, and every
mountain and island were moved out of
their places.
And the kings of the earth and the great
men and the rich men and the chief
captains and the mighty men and every
bondman and every freeman hid themselves
in the dens and in the rocks of the
mountains.
And they said to the mountains and
rocks,
"Fall on us
and hide us from the face of him that
sitteth on the throne
and from the wrath of the Lamb.
For the great day of his wrath is come.
And who shall be able to stand?"
Now, you notice what I didn't notice
what I didn't notice in reading this?
Nowhere
where nuclear bombs went off in the
earth.
Right.
>> Right. All this took place in heaven.
Sun and the moon.
That's the second heaven.
And the stars.
Now, heaven rolled back like a scroll.
That's the water between the second
heaven
and the third heaven where the Father
and
and Jesus and all the angels.
Now, a man had made a a nuclear weapon
so powerful that it can blow up the sun
and the moon and blow down the stars
and make
heaven
roll back like a scroll? That's between
the third and second heaven where the
Father is?
I didn't read that.
Let's see what else is happening during
that time.
Let's go into Matthew the 24th chapter.
Read verses 27 and 30.
27 through uh
27 rather, then skip down to verse 29
and read from 29 to 30.
27 first.
For as the lightning cometh out of the
east
and shineth even to the west,
so shall also the coming of the Son of
man be.
Verse 29.
>> Go ahead.
Immediately
Immediately after the tribulation of
those days
shall the sun be darkened and the moon
shall not give her light.
And the stars shall fall from heaven.
And the powers of heaven shall be
shaken.
And then
shall appear the sign of the Son of man
in heaven.
And then shall all the tribes of the
earth mourn.
And they shall see the Son of man
coming in the clouds of heaven
with power and great glory.
And he shall send his angels with a
great sound of a trumpet. And they shall
gather together his elect from the four
winds
from one end of heaven
to the other.
Now, that's when he's going to recover
Israel from one end of the earth. That's
terminal
to the other.
But look, we see all this big action
took place in heaven.
Right.
So, let's see what's going to happen
that the Lord is going to come. Let's go
Let's go to the one other place.
Let's go into Zechariah 14th chapter.
Read verses three and four and skip down
to 12.
Then shall the Lord go forth and fight
against those nations
as when he fought in the day of battle.
And his
His feet shall stand in that day upon
the Mount of Olives
which is before Jerusalem on the east.
The Mount of Olives shall cleave in the
midst thereof toward the east and toward
the west.
And there shall be a very great great
valley.
And half of the mountain shall be moved
toward the north and half of it toward
the south.
Now, that's when the Lord come.
His feet going to hit that Mount Mount
of Olives on the earth
and it's going to split. That's the only
thing I see where we see some trouble on
the earth. Isn't that correct? Right.
Yep.
Mount of Olives going to split.
You mean all these nuclear weapons going
on and the only thing that's been
affected is the Mount of Olives?
Mhm.
But the Lord is going to bring a plague.
Skip down to verse 12 and read it.
And this shall be the plague wherewith
the Lord shall smite all the people
that have fought against Jerusalem.
Their flesh shall consume away while
they stand upon their feet.
And their eyes shall consume away in
their holes.
And their tongues shall consume away in
their mouths.
Now,
that's some that's some terrible stuff,
isn't it? Mhm.
>> Yep.
This is only the people that has fought
against the Lord.
So, if you had nuclear weapons going on
all over the earth, then why is it that
the only people that fought against the
Lord have these these ugly things happen
to them?
Mhm.
I can't I can't do that.
So, what I must So, now, whatever
whatever congregation
Hebrew class that's teaching this,
I'm going to give that class some real
good advice.
Let's go into Revelation the 20th
chapter.
And we're going to read verse 12.
Revelation 20 and verse 12.
Mhm.
And I saw the dead, small and great,
stand before God.
And the books were opened.
And another book was opened,
which is the book of life.
And the dead were judged out of those
things which were written in the books
according to their works.
Now, the dead was judged according to
those things that were written in the
book.
I didn't see that written in this book
about no nuclear weapons.
Mhm. None listed there.
And if man
and and man will not get to use nuclear
weapons. Oh, he might try, but the Lord
is going to cut it off. I'm going to go
to the one other place and that'll be
it. Let's go back to Matthew the 24th
chapter.
Matthew the 24th.
Because all them nuclear weapons going
on and look like all over the earth,
then
they should kill everybody.
Let's look at Matthew 24.
Let's start reading maybe about Oh,
verse
Mhm.
Uh
let's see.
Verse
Finally Lord Well, you know, what it it
it it when it say in here abomination
desolation. Verse 16
Yeah, 15.
15?
Verse 15, read.
When you therefore shall see the
abomination of desolation spoken of by
Daniel the prophet standing in the holy
place
whoso readeth
let him understand.
Now, why? Read a little more. No, little
more.
Then let them which be in Judea flee
into the mountains.
Let him which is on the house top not
come down to take anything out of his
house.
Neither let him which is in the field
return back to take his clothes.
And woe
>> Now, why is that
Why is that going to be so urgent? Skip
down to verse 21 and go here.
For then shall be great tribulation such
as was not since the beginning of the
world to this time no Mhm. nor ever
shall be.
Go ahead.
And except those days should be
shortened
there should no flesh be saved, but for
the elect sake those days shall be
shortened.
Do now.
Now, it says except those days be
shortened there should be no flesh
saved. Now, if the Lord allowed all
these nuclear weapons to go off all over
the world, then that would kill
everybody.
But he but the Lord will shorten those
days. Sure, they going to want to go to
the nuclear weapon, but the Lord is
going to shorten the days.
He ain't going to let it happen. That's
when he is going to come and put an end
to this thing.
Right. And when I like the like I had
the the the the people in the class
that's teaching this
I asked them one question. How come we
got the sun and the moon and the stars
still there being in America dropped
nuclear bombs on Japan? Right.
I noticed they still there.
Two of them. Two bombs.
Uh-huh. So, I'm saying to those people,
maybe you should uh uh people tell you
stuff like that, tell them to take your
the Bible and and show it to you in the
Bible.
That's one of the big That's one of the
worst mis- uh uh that mis-teaching is is
worse than Satan being in the ground
barbecuing people now. That's all I got
to say.
All right.
And Cornell, please make a correction to
my answer with the calendar.
Julius Caesar moved Julius Caesar moved
the calendar from March to January.
Numa uh Pompilius added the two months,
January and February, but it's still the
Romans.
Okay. Thank you.
All right.
Thank you for that correction and
we're going to move on to our next
question.
Next question. Zion asks in Genesis
5:24,
if no one has been to heaven and Enoch
didn't die and Enoch walked with God and
was not for God took him, where is he?
All right. Brother Jerome, being that no
man has went to heaven, where is Enoch?
Well, let's read the verse that they
gave um Genesis 5 and 24.
Genesis 5:24, and Enoch walked with God
and he was not for God took him.
Okay, so
um
w- the Bible don't tell us where he took
Enoch. So, far be it from us to try to
speculate on where he took him, okay?
Now, as far as no man
um is going to heaven
which means Enoch included because we
talking about the third heaven. No man
has gone to the third heaven. We we in
the second heaven all the time if you
flying in airplanes.
Okay, so it's no man's going to the
third heaven. And as far as Enoch um
um he he he didn't die. And if you go to
Genesis the um fifth chapter
everybody mentioned in that chapter it
it identified them as having died.
Literally say they died.
But when you got to Enoch he don't say
he died because he didn't. And you when
you tie with the Hebrews, he said he
didn't see death because he didn't die.
Okay.
That's all I got on that.
He was not found among men.
I I want to throw something in there.
They said if
man has been to heaven. What do you mean
if?
Right.
>> what
Because cuz somebody's questioning
Jesus.
Don't you go to St. John the third
chapter and read what Jesus said.
Yeah, 13.
St. John 3 and 13.
Yeah, what
What he said verse
Read it. And read 12 and 13. This is
Jesus talking here.
>> Okay.
Okay.
If I have told you earthly things and
you believe not how shall you believe if
I tell you of heavenly things? Mhm.
And no man have ascended up to heaven
but he that came down from heaven
even the son of man which is in heaven.
So, ain't nobody And that's Jesus saying
that. Yeah. So, ain't no if no man
Nobody has gone to heaven. So, where is
Enoch? He is the same You know, he just
took him
out of the vision of man.
Right.
>> ain't nothing
Will somebody go and show you where he
got them them angels that he threw out
of heaven?
I think that's in in first or second
Peter and also in Jude. In Jude?
Yeah. Show you how that uh they are
here. A third of an innumer- innumerable
amount of angels is on this earth.
Yeah.
>> And we haven't seen one. Why?
Run that down and read it.
Uh which one? Second Peter 2, pick it up
at the four.
Second Peter 2?
Second Peter 2 and 4. Yeah.
For if God spared not the angels that
sinned, but cast them down to hell and
delivered them into chains of darkness
to be reserved unto judgment.
Now, this here let's come with the earth
here.
They on the chains of darkness. Well,
read all of them.
Uh Jude
uh
1 and 6. Yeah.
And the angels which kept not their
first estate
but left their own habitation he hath
reserved in everlasting chains under
darkness unto the judgment of the great
day.
Do now. Enoch is on the same thing. When
it said chains of darkness, that don't
mean
God got them chained with chains.
It mean he have them so you can't see
them, but they here.
Right.
>> Yeah. Like Enoch is here.
He didn't go to heaven.
And there ain't no place else to go. So,
all he did was he took him from among
men from from from men being able to see
him.
But he still here.
That's all I have to say.
Like the man still here.
Yeah, it just says Enoch was translated
that he should not see death.
That's it.
Yep.
Yeah, and he was translated to a spirit
being. Just like angels are spirit
beings.
You can't see beings
unless they want to be seen or either
God want you to see him.
Yep.
All right.
>> No man has
Ain't no if. It's an absolute. Jesus
said they haven't. That's all I wanted
to say.
All right. Yeah, needed that correction.
All right.
We're going to move on to our next one
with the time check.
Moving on, the time is 8:08. At a comma
salad asks in reading Leviticus 15:19
how does one practically deal with this
law when his wife is having the issue of
blood?
All right. Jerome, share some light on
that Leviticus 15:19
and they want to know about dealing with
this law of the issue of blood.
Okay. Leviticus 15:19, Tenzel, when you
get go ahead and read it.
And if a woman have an issue and her
issue in her flesh be blood, she shall
be put apart seven days.
And whosoever touches her shall be
unclean unto the evening.
And it said
whosoever touches her shall be unclean
unto the evening. And
if you continue to read in this chapter
whatever she touched, if you touch that
which she touches, you become unclean,
okay? So
if you can avoid having contact with
your wife with you with you cuz you said
your wife you know, if you can avoid
having contact with her for the seven
days she's supposed to be separated you
know, then do it.
But if you know you can't do it, then
more likely within that time span you're
going to be unclean cuz you're either
going to touch some touch her or touch
something that she touched. So, you're
going to be unclean. All right? But at
the point of time when
she's uh
the 7 days and she you know,
become clean,
then there's a better chance that you
can become clean, too, because now uh
she she's clean and then you going it
tell you to wash your clothes and wash
your flesh and be unclean until the
evening, okay?
But if she constantly unclean and you
touching things she touching, you're
going to be constantly unclean, okay?
But when she become clean, then
there's better chance when you wash your
clothes and wash your flesh, you will be
clean in the evening because you're not
constantly being made unclean by her and
the things that she touching, okay?
That's all I got on there. Anybody want
to add?
All right.
Thank you for that, brother. As we move
on to our next question.
Next one. N Y N Y says, "I have been
seeing the same number. I woke up at
3:00 a.m. this morning to my laptop
randomly on with the same number was on
the screen. What does the Bible say
about finding meaning in numbers?" All
right. What does the Bible say about
numbers and their meaning, Julius?
The Lord uses certain numbers in the
Bible, sisters and brothers, for his
purposes.
Uh for our needs, such as the how we
count the feast days and how to keep the
feast days, and our edification.
But not for us to be to worship them
because when you become over obsessed
with numbers, that is called you're not
you're dealing with numerology.
Numerology is a form of divination.
Let's go to Deuteronomy 18th chapter.
And then I'm going to give you a couple
of examples.
Because you can mess around and become
obsessed with them numbers and numbers
can lead and guide you and you can end
up serving or worshipping them.
Deuteronomy 18, we're going to read
verse 9 through 11. Deuteronomy 18:10
through verse 9 through 11. When you get
it, my brother, go ahead.
When thou art come into the land which
the Lord thy God giveth thee, thou shalt
not learn to do after the abomination of
those nations. This nation deals with
these nations deal with astrology,
stargazing. We're not supposed to do
that. Go ahead.
There shall not be found among you
anyone that maketh his son or his
daughter to pass through the fire,
Uh-huh. or that useth divination or an
observer of times, Now, that divination
is divine stuff. You're dealing with the
occult.
Numerology is a branch of knowledge that
deals with the occult
and the significance of numbers.
That's what people get into. Well, this
mean that Oh, this is my number. Oh,
that Now you're going to go to buying
dream books and horoscope stuff and all
that kind of stuff. Over belief in
numbers.
Keep it where it's supposed to be
according to the word of God. Finish it,
brother. Or that useth divination,
or an observer of times, Uh-huh. or a
charmer, Uh-huh. or witch, Yes. or
charmer, All this is divination,
branches of divination. Go ahead. or a
consulter with familiar spirits,
or wizard,
or necromancer.
All Sometimes that's good, brother.
Sometimes you get over obsessed with
things like that. But this all this
stuff is part of what Satan can lead you
to do. Let me show you
a couple of things what God said how to
observe. Let's go to Revelation the 13th
chapter.
The numbers that we use in the Israel of
God is according to the wisdom and
understanding of God to identify things.
Revelation 13 and we Give me verse 18.
And you got it. That's why the Lord uses
these numbers for to fulfill prophecy,
to show us, to instruct us, to guide us,
not to be worshipped, not to become over
dependent upon them. Verse 18, read it.
Here is the wisdom. Let him that hath
understanding count the number of the
beast.
For it is the number of a man. Uh-huh.
And his number is 600 603 score and 6.
So, now he said
this is the number of a man.
We know that that whoever has that
number represents the office of the
Vicarius Filii Dei or the Pope, the
replacement of God on Earth. We're
looking for this cat, this guy who's
going to come. And we recognize him by
the number that God give us because it
is the number of a man.
Okay? That's the number of a man. We
know that will be who or whoever it be
that fulfills the office of the Pope to
fulfill the scripture. Then the Lord
gives you numbers at least five times he
give you the numbers of the great
tribulation period. 1,260 days.
That's 1260. The number 42, still 42
months, still 3 and 1/2 years. Or time,
times, and the dividing of time, still 3
and 1/2 years, which is the duration
duration of the great tribulation to
fulfill prophecy, not to be obsessed in.
To watch when the time come, we can Now
we can say this prophecy is going on now
or or it's being fulfilled.
So,
you got to be careful when you get off
into the
you can actually get off into
numerology.
You know, now you got books out here.
Seven is completion and it and it is,
but you got to use it according to
context of scripture and not lean to
your own understanding
or your purposes. That's all I got. I
hope that helped. Anybody else?
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Be cautious of the numerology. Yes, sir.
>> Let's move on to our next question.
Next question. Deborah Walder asked for
you to explain Isaiah 19:24
and 25.
Isaiah 19:24
Brother Jerome.
Let's go read it.
When you get it, Tazadaq, go ahead and
read.
Isaiah 19:24
and 25.
In that day shall Israel be
the third with Egypt and with Assyria,
even a blessing in the midst of the
land.
Whom the Lord of hosts shall bless,
saying,
"Blessed be Egypt, my people, and
Assyria, the work of my hands, and
Israel, my inheritance." Mhm.
And this will be
during the time when the Lord returns.
And when the Lord return,
a lot of nations going
um
become a part of the
family of God. They're going you know,
they're going to become his children. In
other In other words, they're going to
be servants of the Lord. The Lord going
to adopt them
just like he adopting us
right now through his word. When he come
back, a lot of people going come into
the adoption through the word. They
going you know, not just the Syrians
or the Egyptians, okay? So,
um
Let's go to I want to show you example
of that in that Revelations
the 7th chapter.
And let's read verse 9 and 10 then we'll
skip.
Revelations 7
verse 9 and 10 then we're going to skip.
Revelations 7:9 and 10. After this I
beheld and lo, a great multitude, which
no man could number, of all nations and
kindreds and people and tongues, stood
before the throne and before the Lamb,
clothed with white robes and palms in
their hands,
and cried with a loud voice, saying,
"Salvation to our God which sitteth upon
the throne and unto the Lamb." And skip
down read verse 13 through 17.
And one of the elders answered, saying
unto me, "What are these which are
arrayed in white robes, and whence came
they?"
And I said unto him, "Sir, thou
knowest." And he said to me, "These are
they which came out of great
tribulation, and have washed washed
their robes and made them white in the
blood of the Lamb.
So, therefore are are they before the
throne of God, and serve him day and
night in his temple.
And he that sitteth upon the throne
shall dwell among them.
They shall hunger no more, neither
thirst anymore. Neither shall the sun
light on them, nor any heat. For the
Lamb which is in the midst of the throne
shall feed them, and shall lead them
unto living fountains of water. And God
shall wipe away all tears from their
eyes." Yeah. And in
Zechariah, the 14th chapter, Mhm. they
going to come up from year to year and
he specifically mentioned the Egyptians.
If they don't come up, he said he ain't
going to let it rain rain. That's right.
>> on them, you know, and when they got to
come up from year to year to keep the
feast.
Yeah. That's That's all I got.
That's right. Like you said, Jerome, all
nations. Yes, sir. Let me make it
through it.
Yes, sir. Okay.
Now, you know, uh
Let's go into Romans the 9th chapter
and read from 1 down to 4.
Down to 5.
All right. Read it when you get it.
I say the truth in Christ. I lie not. My
conscience also bearing me witness in
the Holy Ghost.
That I have great heaviness and
continual sorrow in my heart.
For I could wish that myself were cursed
from Christ for my brother, my kinsmen
according to the flesh,
who are Israelites,
to whom pertaineth the adoption and the
glory and the covenant
>> And that's enough.
And that's enough. That to who are
Israelites to whom
pertaineth the adoption.
See, Jacob, our father name was Jacob.
The Lord adopted Jacob, changed his name
to Israel and and other words, he
adopted the whole nation of Israel.
But let's show you what the Lord said
when he sent Moses down to Egypt. Let's
go into Exodus
the fourth chapter.
And
uh uh
we going
I'm going to get down to where it says
reason, brother. Israel is my son.
Read 19
and then skip down and read verse 22.
And the Lord said unto Moses in Midian,
go,
return into Egypt, for all the men are
dead which sought thy life.
Uh-huh.
Verse 22.
>> 22.
And thou shalt say unto Pharaoh, thus
saith the Lord, Israel is my son,
even my firstborn.
And I say unto thee, let my son go, that
he may serve me.
And if thou refuse to let him go,
behold, I will slay thy sons, even thy
firstborn.
Okay, now. That lets you know that
Israel is not the only son. He is just
the firstborn.
That's why Paul told you in Romans
Israel for long the adoption. But when
the Lord come, he's going to adopt all
the rest of the nation during the
millennium period, including Egypt. And
who the other one he said? Syrians.
Syrians.
Syrians? Okay. And everybody else.
By the end of the millennium period, the
thousand years of peace, everybody's
going to be named Israel. Yeah.
Right now, it is firstborn and the rest
going to come later. That's all I have
to say.
All right.
Thank you for that.
As we continue to move on to our next
question.
Moving on. Attica Masala says, for many
years when I do
random things, something totally random
happens at exactly the same time. Could
there be a spiritual understanding of
why this happens every single time?
All right. Random things at random time.
Brother Drake.
Could there be a spiritual reason as to
why this is happening? So, it's it's two
ways we could look at it. Let's go over
to Ecclesiastes 5
and we going to read one verse there.
Ecclesiastes 5 and we going to read
verse 3.
When you get there, Tamsel, read that
verse.
For a dream cometh through the multitude
of business. And a fool's voice is known
by multitude of words. So, the scripture
say that a dream come through a
multitude of business. You know, you
could have a lot on your mind during the
day
and have a lot of activities that you
going through. You could watch a movie
and eat something late at night and then
you have a dream about it as a result.
Does that have any spiritual
significance?
No.
But let's go over to Job 33.
Job 33
and we going to read
verses
14.
14 to 16. Go ahead when you get it,
brother.
For God speaketh once,
yea, twice, yet man perceiveth not. Mhm.
In a dream, in a vision of the night,
when deep sleep falleth upon men, in
slumbering upon the bed,
then he openeth the ears of men and
sealth their instruction. Now, notice
here says God speaketh, yea, once,
twice, but man don't perceive it.
He say sometimes in the dream and the
visions of the night.
He says, then he openeth the ears of men
and sealth their instruction. So, in
that they are instructed.
So, does that have spiritual
significance? Yes.
But as to you having a dream randomly,
are you randomly experiencing something
and then randomly something else
happening? I can't answer that for you.
It's just like Julius spoke earlier
about that you have to try the spirits
and and see whether they are from God or
not and you got to do that by the word
of God. Joseph had a dream.
You know, Peter had a dream, a vision,
you know, and and the Lord prepared him
for what he had to do.
But it doesn't mean that that's the case
for you because we also read that dreams
happen through a multitude of business.
That's all I got. Yeah, you right,
brother. It also says that in a
multitude of dreams it can also be
diverse vanities. Sometimes they don't
mean nothing. That's right. That's
right.
>> Yep.
All right. Thank you for that answer,
brother. As we continue to move on to
our next one.
Moving on. Skywriter asks,
what does it mean when Jesus said, go ye
and tell that fox in Luke 13 verse 32.
Why did he call the guy a fox? All
right, Drake. Go and tell that old fox.
Where did he say it?
Well, it's a description. It's a
description describing a person's
character or nature. But let's go read
it. Go ahead.
Luke 13 and and read that verse,
brother.
Start at 31? 30 Yeah, you can start at
31. Read 31 to 32.
The same day there came certain of the
Pharisees saying unto him, get thee out
and depart hence, for Herod will kill
thee. Mhm.
>> And he said unto them, go ye and tell
that fox, behold, I cast out devils
and I do cures today and tomorrow and
the third day I shall be perfect. So,
the Pharisees said that, but that don't
mean that that was so, that Herod was
looking for him, but he is saying, tell
that fox, today I cast out devils. So,
he's talking about the character,
you know, uh of that or the nature of
the individual. Let's look at that one
more time. Let's go to Isaiah 56 and see
another character describe our nature.
Isaiah 56 and read verse 10. Isaiah 56
and 10. Go ahead, brother, when you get
it.
His watchmen are blind. They are all
ignorant. They are all dumb dogs. They
cannot bark, sleeping, lying down,
loving to slumber. So, he not talking
about these watchmen
being dogs,
but he's giving a description or the of
the nature and the character of them. He
says they are dumb dogs that cannot
bark, lying down, loving to slumber.
This is their characteristics and their
nature. Read verse 11 and that's it. Go
ahead.
Yea, they are they are greedy dogs which
can never have enough. Mhm. That's good
enough.
That's good enough. They are greedy
dogs, but they not dogs, they are
watchmen, blind,
ignorant,
dumb,
cannot bark. What good is a dog that
can't bark?
That's That's all I got.
Yeah. We do it all the time, Brother
Drake. We call people a low-down snake
in the grass. Yes, sir.
Yeah. There was There was a There was a
little spiritual side to that, too.
And that is uh uh
what he said that uh
What he said to D?
Uh uh
Go and tell the little fox
Behold, I cast out devils.
And I do
uh
What's this?
verse
D
And and and
And let me read it again.
Yes, sir. Let's go back to that Luke
uh 13 13
And he said unto them,
"Go ye and tell that fox,
'Behold, I cast out devils, and I do
cures today and tomorrow.
And the third day I shall be perfect.'"
Perfected.
>> That's That's
That's the spiritual part when he's
saying the third day I will be perfect.
Now, let's go to Matthew's. That's what
it said 12 where he said how many days
he's going to be in the grave?
Yes, sir. Three days. Matthew 12: 38
through 40.
Go and read it.
Then certain of the scribes and of the
Pharisees answered, saying, "Master,
we would see a sign from thee."
But he answered and said unto them,
"An evil and adulterous generation
seeketh after a sign.
And there shall no sign be given to it,
but the sign of the prophet Jonas.
For as Jonas was three days and three
nights in the
whale's belly, so shall the Son of man
be three days and three nights in the
heart of the earth."
Now, when he come up out of the earth,
he going to be He rose on the third day,
didn't he?
Yes, sir.
And then he was He went in the grave as
man, he come out as God on the third
day.
And that is what made him perfect
because he was God again. We're going to
read Hebrews 10:1. And that'll be it.
Hebrews 10:1
For the law,
having a shadow of good things to come,
and not the very image of the things,
can never with those sacrifices which
they offer year by year continually make
the comers thereunto perfect.
No, so blood of animals can't You can't
get salvation become God by being with
the animal blood, but by the Jesus blood
of Jesus
you can become God. And that's when you
be
When you be perfect. So he said, "You
tell You know, so that's the spiritual
part he was telling me."
I do what I do, but but I you know
Yeah, the old fox is going to kill me.
You know, they going to uh but Israel
going to put them up to kill me.
However,
I'll be in the grave three days and
three nights. On the third day I will
rise, and I will I will be made perfect.
That's meaning he going to rise from the
grave. He'll be God again. That's all I
have to say.
That's right. Yes, sir.
>> All right.
Thank you for that.
As we move on to our next question.
Next one, Kenya V
Haynes asks, "In Titus 1:2,
eternal life was promised before the
world began. Is there any other
scriptures that speaks on this as well?"
It's all about keeping the commandments
of God if you want that eternal life.
But let's go to Titus 1. Titus 1.
And when you get there, brother,
pick it up at that verse 1.
Go ahead.
Paul,
a servant of God, and an apostle of
Jesus Christ,
according to the faith of God's elect,
and the acknowledging of the truth which
is after godliness,
Yes.
in hope of eternal life, which God that
cannot lie promised before the world
began.
Yeah, promised before the world began
because he sent nothing but truth and
godliness.
But man had a problem with it, even Adam
and Eve. Go ahead. Verse 3.
But having due time manifested his word
through preaching,
Through preaching.
Go ahead.
which is committed unto me according to
the commandments of God our savior.
Yes, preaching cuz even Jesus himself
came preaching when he was in the flesh.
And let's turn over to Mark 10. Mark 10.
And when you get there, brother, pick it
up at that verse
17 for me. Mark 10 and verse
17.
Go ahead.
And when he was gone forth into the way,
there came one running and kneeled to
him,
and asked him,
"Good master,
what should I do that I may have eternal
life?"
Yeah, this guy was asking, "What shall
he do that he may have eternal life?" Go
ahead.
And Jesus said unto him, "Why callest
thou me good?
There is none good but one. And thou
>> going to speak about the commandments,
Tenzel. Go ahead.
"Thou knowest the commandments. Do not
commit adultery. Do not kill. Do not
steal. Do not bear false witness.
Defraud not. Honor thy father and
mother."
So it was always been about them
commandments and doing what thus says
the Lord. Now, turn over to John 14
right quick.
John 14, and then we going to go to John
10, and then that'll be it for me. John
and pick it up at that verse 15. Go
ahead.
"If you love me, keep my commandments."
Yes, always about the commandments. If
you love Jesus, keep his commandments.
Verse 23.
Jesus answered and said unto unto them
unto him, "If a man love me, he will
keep my words.
And my father will love him. And we will
come unto him, and make our abode with
him."
Yes, there we go again with the eternal
life. You can keep reading down, not
you, Tenzel, but whoever is asking that
question. Let's go to John 10, one more
place.
John 10 and read 27 and 28.
John 10:27
and 28.
Cuz this will get you eternal life.
Go ahead.
"My sheep hear my voice.
And I know them, and they follow me.
Mhm. And I give unto them eternal life.
And they shall never perish. Neither
shall any man pluck them out of my
hand."
Yes. And so we talking about eternal
life and keeping those commandments.
And that's all I got. Anybody else want
to add?
Let's go to 1 Corinthians 15th chapter.
1 Corinthians the 15th chapter.
Uh-huh.
All right.
You going to read from verse
uh
49 and 52.
All right.
>> 53
53. Go ahead when you get it.
"And as we have borne the image of the
earthly, we shall also bear the image of
the heavenly."
Uh-huh.
"Now this I say, brethren, that flesh
and blood cannot inherit the kingdom of
God.
Neither do corruption inherit
incorruption.
Behold, I show you a mystery.
We shall not all sleep, but we shall all
be changed
in a moment,
in the twinkling of an eye,
at the last trump.
For the trumpet shall sound, and the
dead shall be raised incorruptible,
and we shall be changed.
For this corruptible must put on
incorruption,
and this mortal must put on
immortality."
Mhm.
So So this, you know, so when you become
an immortal, that means you going to get
eternal life. That's all I wanted to
show.
All right.
Yes, sir.
>> Thank you for that. As we continue,
sister, with a time check to our next
question.
Yes, the time is 8:38. Mrs. Martin asks
for you to share some light about urns.
She says, "I understand you cannot
have urns in your house, but can you
bury a
cremated loved one on your property?"
Yeah, that's true. You're not supposed
to have an urn in your house or in your
garage or on your property. But can you
bury a loved one on your property? Some
laws some lands allow for that. But you
you'd be turning your yard into a
cemetery if you don't have to bury
someone on your own property, but some
lands do allow it.
And the states that do allow it require
that you have a burial permit. You're
not supposed to just do it on your own.
You're supposed to check with your
uh local city or your county and get
some paperwork from them in order to do
that. But, you know, like the Lord say,
"For dust thou art, unto dust thou shall
return." And some cemeteries will return
the ashes and the urn to the dust for
you.
So, um that's something that you can
also
consider.
Um
some military people, they have
set their ashes uh in the lakes and in
the rivers, you know, so those are some
options that people have done, too, but
it depends on where you stay in order to
be able to do that, but
anybody else want to add?
All right. We'll leave it right there as
we move on to our next question. Well,
time is a ticking.
Yes, moving on. Black Mole Black Mole
asks, "Is the
Is the Apocrypha part of the original
Bible?
If so, what scriptures can I show?
If not, what scriptures can I show?"
So, guest caller, is the Apocrypha a
part of the original Bible?
No.
Because Lord spoke to Moses.
Yep.
Everybody after Moses,
they came up out of Israel.
Mhm.
>> Israel is
priest of God.
Lord tell you in 147 Psalm
that Israel uh he showed Israel his uh
uh uh
his word and Jacob, you know, his
statutes. He have not done that with any
other nation.
That's right.
And when you go to Isaiah, I think it's
around 43, he said, "Israel uh uh uh are
his uh uh uh
They're going to show forth his praise.
Yep. They chapter Roman,
uh Israel the oracles of God is in the
hand of Israel. The ninth chapter Romans
will tell you that to Israel belong the
the law, the giving of the law, the
service of God.
So,
the Apocrypha, I know it was written by
uh written by somebody else other than
Israel.
Plus again, too,
it lets you know that the prophet
Apocrypha contradicts the word of God in
a whole lot of places.
But, if you go and read in Apocrypha,
it'll tell you that God created Adam
without a soul.
Mhm.
But, when you go into uh Genesis 2 and
7, it tell that the Lord God formed man
out of the dust of the ground and
breathed into his nostrils breath of
life and man became a soul.
Right. First Corinthians 15th chapter,
verse 45 tell you that the first man
Adam was made a living soul.
So, how is it that God going to create
you man without a soul?
Mhm.
Apocrypha
contradicts the Bible. It's got a whole
lot of stuff wrong. I said, when people
read the Apocrypha, if they read it, cuz
I got one.
You have to be crazy to believe a lot of
that stuff. It tell you about the you
got the eagle that come up out of the
sea
with so many wing feathers on each wing
and he have three heads and he rule the
earth.
Mhm.
So, Wow.
>> Look at all this contradiction. It said
Edras,
I guess supposed to be a prophet,
he was taken to heaven. Well, Jesus say
ain't nobody been to heaven.
So, that's not a part of the Bible
because it's contradict
and you can tell that it was written by
somebody
other than Israel. And Jesus told I'll
tell you what Jesus told the woman at
the well. When she told him, "Our
fathers worship the Lord in these
mountains."
He said, "Woman, you worship you know
not what."
Yep.
The salvation is of the Jews.
Apocrypha was written by
somebody else. I believe it was Edom cuz
I heard an Edomite rabbi say that uh we
are a fully developed spirit in heaven.
So, God created a flesh and blood in
order to a flesh and blood body in order
to live on on the earth.
And so, we took over that body. So, when
the body die, our spirit goes on back to
heaven.
In other words,
he created man,
Adam, without a soul and the soul had to
come for uh from heaven and take over
Adam's body.
Mhm.
That's not Bible. This contradicts the
Bible, sister and brother.
And if you read the Apocrypha, there's a
whole lot of contradiction. I mean, a
whole lot. A lot of it.
And they and it was not written by
Israel.
Mhm.
And in the Bible, every book from
Genesis to Revelation was written
written by Israelites.
Yeah.
>> Because Israel
are the ones that God worked through and
he told you that. That's all I have to
say. Yes, caller, can we read Can we
read Isaiah 8 and just verse 20?
Go read it.
Isaiah 8
and 20.
To the law and to the testimony.
If they speak not according to this
word, it is because there is no light in
them.
Simple as that. This word come with this
Bible.
You people act like God don't have the
power
to control this Bible. Some of the
Catholic Church took the That's because
somebody else has added to it.
It was the hand of the Lord that threw
all of the extra garbage out of it. Book
of Enoch. They Enoch used to rule the
earth.
Now, he's in heaven ruling for God.
Mhm.
Yeah.
Wow.
>> There's so many so much so much stuff
there I see. You have to be
almost mentally
unstable
to even think that the Apocrypha is a
part of the word of God.
Or either you simply do not believe the
King James version of the Bible or any
Bible.
That's all I have to say.
Yep.
You're right, brother. All we need is
Genesis to Revelation. That's it.
That's it.
Yep.
All right. We hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Moving on. JB says,
"Is there a scripture of where you ask
the Lord for something, he gives it to
you, but now you no longer want it or
need it?
Is this evil?"
Yes, caller. You ask the Lord for
something.
I I you know, I'm trying to wrap my mind
around what you said. I guess it depends
on what you ask him for.
You know.
>> Mhm.
So,
I don't know. I can't answer that
question.
Okay. Then, we'll go leave it right
there as we move on to our next
question. Give it to you. Moving on.
Steven Gugu asks, "In Genesis 3:18
and 2 Corinthians
12:7,
when it mentions thorns and thistles, is
this the Lord bringing in mental or
physical disabilities,
infirmities to us due to man sinning?"
All right, brother Dre. We know sinning
has gotten the whole world in trouble.
What does the book say, brother? Let's
go to Genesis 3, read verses 17 and 18.
Go ahead, Tanzael, when you get it.
And unto Adam he said, "Because thou has
hearkened to the voice of thy wife
and has eaten of the tree of which I
commanded thee, saying, thou shall not
eat of it.
Cursed is the ground for thy sake.
In sorrow shall thou eat of it all the
days of thy life.
Thorns also and thistles shall it bring
forth to thee.
Thou shall eat the herbs of the field."
So, because of Adam's sin,
the ground was cursed among other things
that happened.
And it said that it's going to bring
forth thorns and thistles. Mhm. This is
part of that, but let's go over to the
other passage of scripture now.
2 Corinthians
12 and read verse 7.
2 Corinthians 12 and verse 7.
Go ahead, brother, when you get it.
And lest I should be exalted above
measure through the abundance of the
revelations,
there was given to me a thorn in the
flesh,
the messenger of Satan to buffet me,
lest I should be exalted above measure.
And so, here in this passage,
Paul said a thorn was given to him in
his flesh
and lest he be exalted above measure.
A messenger of Satan buffeted him.
And and this thorn was the buffeting
that he got in his flesh.
But
here's the thing. Does that mean that
that is the case?
No, let's let's go to
uh
John now. Let's go to John 9.
John 9 and we going to pick it up at
verse 1. Read verse 1 to 3.
And skip.
Go ahead when you get it, brother.
And as Jesus passed by, he saw a man
which was blind from his birth. Mhm.
And his disciples asked him saying,
"Master, who did sin?
This man or his parents
that he was born blind?" So So they
asked
the disciples asked Jesus, "Who Who
sinned? Did this man sin or his parents
that he was born blind?" Go ahead.
Jesus answered,
"Neither have this man sinned nor his
parents,
but that the works of God should be made
manifest in him."
Now, you see that? Jesus said, "Hey,
neither his parents nor did this man sin
that he was born this way, but that the
works of God should be made manifest."
Now, skip down. Read verse 6 and 7.
When he had thus spoken, he spat on the
ground and made clay of the spittle. And
he anointed the eyes of the blind man
with the clay. Mhm.
And said unto him, "Go wash in the pool
of Siloam,
which is by interpret tation sent."
He went his way therefore and washed and
came seeing. So that blind man, after he
did what God what Jesus told him to do,
that man came back not blind anymore. He
came back seeing.
So that In that particular case,
it it had nothing to do with whether or
not this was from the beginning. But
this is what I want you to note
is Revelation the 21st chapter.
Because the Lord speaks about a time
that if we endure in whatever we going
through, God is promising us to take
away all this stuff that we may be
experiencing now or our loved ones are
experiencing.
So I just want to encourage you to
endure.
That's all I got.
Yeah.
All right.
Thank you for that, brother. As we move
on to our next question.
Moving on, JB asked, "Are we allowed to
choose our occupation
or the Lord give us a specific job based
on his will?"
All right. We'll open this up to the
panel. It seem like That's a two-part
question and seem like both would apply.
You know, are we allowed to choose our
occupation?
Yeah, and do the Lord sometimes give you
a specific job based on his will?
Yeah. I'll say both.
>> something
I want to throw in something real big.
Yes, sir.
>> And then we looking at
things that's small.
Now, the biggest thing that the Lord
uh want us to do
is
get salvation.
Yeah. And let's see who
he put in here. Let's go to Deuteronomy
the 30th chapter.
We going to start reading at verse 11.
And uh
We going to read down to verse 15.
Okay.
For this commandment which I command
thee this day,
it is not hidden from thee, neither is
it far off.
It is not in heaven that thou shouldest
say,
"Who shall go up for us to have it and
bring it unto us that we may hear it and
do it?
Neither is it beyond the sea
that thou shouldest say, "Who shall go
over the sea for us and bring it unto us
that we may hear it and do it?"
But the word is very nigh unto thee,
in thy mouth
and in thy heart, that thou mayest do
it.
See, I have set before thee this day
life and good and death and evil.
Now, the Lord said that. And then he
told you to keep his commandments.
Get down to verse 19.
Skip down and read verse 19.
I call heaven and earth to record this
day against you that I have set before
you life and death,
blessing and cursing.
Therefore choose life that both thou and
thy seed may live.
Now, the Lord gave made you a free
agent.
Mhm.
>> before you life and
death. In other words, he going to put
his laws and statutes before you. But he
told you to choose. That's between
That's you making a choice between
eternal life and eternal death.
Yeah.
>> So why is God dictating what kind of
career you going to have?
Huh.
Your choice.
That's all I have to say.
All right.
We'll leave it right there as we move on
to our next question.
Next one. Navy Doc asked about crock
pots. Uh he or she states, "I was
talking to a IOG member who said if you
cook a meal in the crock pot before the
Sabbath day comes in and once the meal
is complete, you leave it in the warmer
during the Sabbath. Is it not considered
kindling a fire because you cooked it
before the Sabbath?" He said he also
confirmed this with another IOG member
who said it was not considered kindling
the fire. Is this correct?
Mhm.
Brother Julius, how you going to cook it
and leave it still warm at night?
Cuz it's plugged in.
Yeah.
Because it's plugged in. You got crock
pots that have settings on it.
The setting is low,
high, warm.
And once the food is cooked,
did that guest call her?
I ain't saying nothing.
Once the food is cooked, it is done.
Unplug your crock pot because a warmer
is still
although the food is cooked, something
is keeping it warm.
Something is keeping it warm. So you
have gas ranges, you have electrical
ranges. The electrical range has a
warming drawer where you put it in there
and there's a
special pilot light that's keeping that
thing that's lit up that's keeping it
warm.
You got a warming drawer. So you still
got uh things and apparatus that's
keeping it warm because it's plugged in.
It's plugged in. Let's go to Let's look
at what the book say because we find all
kinds of ways to pollute the Lord's
Sabbath day because we got to have hot
or warm food.
Let's go to
I'm sorry. Exodus the 16th chapter uh
Tenzel.
Exodus the 16th chapter.
Cuz you're still using electricity.
Right.
You want to keep your stuff your food
warm? Once it's cooked, hey,
put it in a insulated
um
thermos or insulated stainless steel
container.
Wrap it in aluminum foil and and and and
you know, but the bottom line is
we try to find way Look at what the Lord
said. Exodus 16 and when you get it my
brother Tenzel, read verse 23.
And he said unto them, "This is that
which the Lord have said.
Tomorrow is the rest of the holy Sabbath
unto the Lord. Yes.
Bake that which ye will bake today
Today.
and seethe that ye will seethe
and that which remaineth, overlay it up
for you to be kept until the morning.
Hey, overlay wrap it up. Put it up. But
you can't cook on the Sabbath day. You
can't warm on the Sabbath day using
electricity or no kind of apparatus
because you are still changing the
condition of the food trying to keep it
warm.
Trying to keep it warm. Uh read verse
28.
Verse 28. I don't care if it come from
Listen, going to church don't make you
straight. It is obedience that make you
straight. Right.
>> Verse 28. Go ahead. And the Lord said
unto Moses, "How long refuse ye to keep
my commandments and my laws? Man, work
six days.
On the seventh day, rest. Cook your food
on the sixth day. It's called a day of
preparation. On the seventh day,
keep the Sabbath holy. Stop trying to
get around the Lord's laws, statutes,
and commandments. One more place. First
Peter.
First Peter 4.
It's not hard. I gave you six days to do
whatever you want to do your labor.
But remember the Sabbath day and keep it
holy. That's why he put remember
therefore.
Right.
When you get it, 1 Peter 4 and just one
verse, verse 17.
This is a warning. This is a caution. It
go for me or anybody else out here. Go
ahead.
But this time is come
that judgment must begin at the house of
God.
And if it first begin at us,
what shall the end be of them that obey
not the gospel of God? I do not want to
be a victim of this verse.
Just remember the Sabbath day and keep
it holy. When the sun go down on the
seventh day, man,
light it up. Torch it up. Grill it up.
Boil it up. Go back to what you're
doing. But that one day, let's do
better. That's all I got.
Mhm. Yeah. Yes, sir. And Brother Julius,
I know it's in that question they said
because they confirmed it with another
member. They felt as though what they
was doing was right. That does not
necessarily mean that you got the right
answer. We read in the in the We read in
the lesson earlier in this lesson, let
the word of God be true and every man a
lie. Right. What did the book say?
Right. Question answered. Let's see if
we finish the rest of them.
Okay. Repeat that, guest caller.
So the questions have been answered.
Let's move on. Yes, sir.
All right. Um
So guest caller, you want to go a little
bit past cuz we got uh
another issue we got to get here cuz
what's the time, Deborah?
It's 9:00.
We got three
>> 9:01.
I'm going to let the guest caller make
that call. You
You want to end it here?
No, we got three more. Let's deal with
them. All right. Let's keep the show
rolling in, Sister Deborah. What is our
next one?
Our next one, Troy Brober asks, do we
have to end a prayer saying in Jesus'
name? And if not, why do we say it?
All right. We wait in the prayer, but
what
What you got to say, Brother Jerome?
What What did Jesus say about it? You
know, Jesus is the author and the
finisher of our salvation.
He the captain of our salvation. So we
And our best bet is to follow his
instructions. So let me share some of
his instruction regarding that with you.
Go to John, the 14th chapter.
And read verse 13. Then we're going to
do the 15th chapter after that, Tenzel.
John 14 verse 13.
And whatsoever you shall ask in my name,
that will I do. That the Father may be
glorified in the Son.
And then read verse the 15th chapter and
read verse 16. Let's tie it together.
Ye have not chosen me, but I have chosen
you and ordained you
that ye should go and bring forth fruit
and that your fruit should remain that
whatsoever ye shall ask of the Father in
my name,
he may give it you.
And that's the author's instruction of
our salvation.
You do well to take heed.
That's all I got.
All right. Yes, sir.
Hope that answered your question. Next
one, Deborah.
Next one, Sandra Allen asks, how do we
know if we're physical Israel? Being
that black people are scattered all
around the world, how can a black person
be sure?
All right. Guest caller.
Well, the question he asked answers it.
The Lord told you in the 28th chapter of
Deuteronomy that you're going to be
scattered all over the world.
>> Got it. That's right. And sold male and
female slaves.
So it depends on how you got there.
I suggest whoever asked this question,
why don't you watch black history?
Then uh the full series. Then you won't
ask a question like this again. You'll
know. That's all I have to say.
That's right. Yeah. Begins in February.
First Sabbath in February. We got five
lessons on that. And if you can't wait
till then, call the office and purchase
you a series. All right.
So we're going to move on, Sister
Deborah, to our final question of the
evening.
Yes, Brother Anthony wants to know in 1
John 5 verses 16 and 17, what is the sin
not unto death?
All right. What is this sin that is not
unto death, Brother Julius?
Uh let's read that scripture, Saint John
5.
Saint John 5.
And when you get it, read 16 and 17.
We'll read that scripture and then we'll
close out.
Is it Is Saint John 5? Was it first
Okay. First John.
First John. First John.
>> First John 5. My apologies. 1 John 5 16
and 17. Go ahead, my brother.
If any man see his brother sin a sin
which is not unto death,
he shall ask and he shall give him life
for them that sin not unto death.
There is a sin unto death. I do not say
that he should pray for it.
Now, what is the sin that is not unto
death? Let's go to Matthew 12. So we got
one verse.
Matthew 12
and verse
31.
And the second
Go ahead.
And the second is like namely this, thou
shalt love thy
>> Matthew 12. My bad. Matthew 12.
Matthew 12 and 31.
Okay.
Wherefore I say unto you, all manner of
sin and blasphemy shall be forgiven unto
men. All There's your answer. All manner
of sin
and blasphemy shall be forgiven unto
men.
But here's the sin that shall not be
forgiven. Go ahead.
The blasphemy against the Holy Ghost
shall not be forgiven unto men.
One more verse.
And whosoever speaketh a word against
the Son of man, it shall be forgiven
him.
You can say Jesus never came
until you find out. But
But go ahead.
But whosoever speaketh against the Holy
Ghost, it shall not be forgiven him.
Neither in this world neither in the
world to come.
So
all manner of sin can be forgiven. You
can steal and be forgiven. You can do uh
what they call
adultery. All All those sins can be
forgiven. But blasphemy against the Holy
Spirit shall not be forgiven in this
world nor the world to come. You calling
sitting in God's seat calling God's word
a lie.
It shall not be forgiven.
In this world nor the world to come.
That's all I got.
Yeah.
And say Brother Julius, even even in
knowing the truth and teaching a lie put
you in big trouble also. Hey, he told
That's what he And that's what he said.
That's what he told these false
prophets. If they don't repent,
the lake of fire will be their
final
destination.
Yeah. All right.
Guest caller.
2 Thessalonians.
And And read verses 9
and
uh there and to 12.
2 Thessalonians Thessalonians 9.
9 and to 12. Read it quickly.
Even him whose coming is after the
working of Satan with all power and
signs and lying wonders
and with all deceivableness
of unrighteousness in them that perish
because they received not the love of
the truth that they might be saved.
And for this
These people that listen to false
doctrine, especially those by the
Catholics, what it's talking about here.
They love the truth.
That means that they that
they love a lie. They don't
believe in the truth. Look what the
Lord's going to do to them. Go ahead.
For this
cause God shall send them strong
delusion
that they might believe a lie.
That they might all be damned who
believe not the truth
but have pleasure in unrighteousness.
Wow. Do not You know what the truth is,
but still you believe a lie and you
teach a lie. Then after a while, the
Lord's going to send you strong
delusion.
That's called a reprobate mind that you
might be damned.
It's the only one
be forgiven from.
Yeah.
No.
That's all I have to say.
All right. Great answer.
All right. Thank you for that.
And Sister Deborah, our time check.
The time is 9:09.
All right. We got a little overtime
tonight. But we want to thank everybody
from all around the world who sent in
those questions. We want to thank you
for tuning in with us.
And we like to say if you sent us a
question and we didn't get to it, please
don't resubmit it. Sister Deborah take
it, put it in rotation, and we will deal
with that question next week. So, until
we all come together again, please be
safe, be blessed, stay prayed up, and
may the Lord have mercy on us all as
Brother Tancel closes us out.
Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in Earth as it is in
heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us of our debts as we
forgive our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation, but
deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom, and the power,
and the glory forever.
In Jesus' name we pray.
Amen.